<Document>
#NANOTRASEN OFFICIAL
[bold]EMPLOYEE INFORMATIONAL GUIDE: SECTOR APPALIA MAJORIS[/bold]

Welcome or welcome back valued family members! You are receiving this document because you have either recently joined the company, or recovered from a severe physical or mental injury requiring cloning and/or amnestisization. To ensure you are properly informed on modern circumstances, this document is to inform you of any and all past threats, so you can react accordingly and appropriately going forward. There has not been any major incidents reported on NT property in years. This is because Nanotrasen values your safety, and has ensured the elimination of any and all risks to your safety.

#Things to remember:
Nanotrasen requires you to remember the following. The following list of information does not apply to command staff or security, who have their own version of this document, to maximize your safety.
ANY potential similarities to items listed on this list should be reported to security IMMEDIATELY, as to best allow for security to remove the potentially traumatic or corporate incompliant material from the station.
Nanotrasen reiterates to you that while many of these threats are real, There has not been any major incidents reported on NT property in years.
	[bold]REMEMBER!!![/bold] Seeing can be believing- Anything you see out of the ordinary should be reported to security to ensure safety and decorum on station.
Misperceptions are bad for morale, so report yourself and what you see on radio, so the psychology staff onside can better assist you. Remember, anything you see is unlikely to be an item listed below.
Information not covered in this document is not restricted, unless said information trade secrets.

Nanotrasen would like to open this document with a reminder, you are our family. As such, for a limited time all mandatory psychiatric evaluations will be billed at half cost!

##THREATS OF THE PAST:

The Syndicate are a known group of corporate ruffians, known to perform acts of terror on enemy corporations. However, the syndicate is no longer active in the sector, and they are not considered a threat to the company.
If any non-Nanotrasen equipment is noticed (likely misplaced in eras gone by), please report it and anyone holding it to security so it can be properly removed.

Gorlex Marauders are an elusive group of terrorists who have historically attacked assets in other sectors. Their actions of terror are commonly seen in popular action movies. Due to their status as mythical raiders, they are seen as figures of fable, and known as “Nukies”.
Corporate assures you that “Nukies” are the stuff of movies at most, would never appear in Appalia, and if there was any threat, Nanotrasen security would be informed and ready for it.

Tiger Co. Changelings are an extinct superpredator species, often seen in other sectors, and in horror movies. Due to the efforts of Nanotrasen CBURN, they have been expunged from all known space and are non threats.
As can be seen in movies, these aberrations sport limited shapeshifting, rapidly mutating limb weapons, and an infinite hunger for flesh. For that reason, they make wonderful horror movie antagonists!
Regardless of their extinction, ANY Changeling Delusion Syndrome (the belief one has seen a ling), should result in a referral to the psychology department, and a security sweep of station, as has been tradition for hundreds of years.

Xenomorphs, Chimeras, Space dragons, and other xenofauna threats, often seen by salvage teams, while trivial, these creatures are known to smuggle themselves aboard stations after chancing upon them.
THESE CREATURES ARE NOT SEVERE THREATS. Regardless, CALL SECURITY IMMEDIATELY ON THE SIGHTING OF ANY NON SENTIENT XENOFAUNA INFESTATION.

Necrotic Viruses, the cause of so called “Zombie” outbreaks, are totally extinct due to the discovery and dispensation of ambuzol.  No further discussion is required due to the extinct nature of the disease.

Rodents and pests are an ongoing challenge for corporate, but a minor issue for the janitors to handle. Any reports of rodents of unusual mass are unfounded, and should be treated with little merit.

Bingles are a low threat pest, which is known to infest stations and steal en masse. They are a danger to the corporate bottom line, and when they occur, should be reported for extermination. They are mildly paralytic, and unarmed crew should avoid them at all costs.

Grey Aliens are a common mass hallucination, and delusions thereof should be reported, but crew should NEVER panic over such rumors.

Revolutions are mere hearsay, and violent detractors are merely plot points in novels. That said, anti corporate propaganda is illegal, and should be reported to security if overheard.

Blobs are hostile xenofauna which will commonly attach to the station and begin to infest them. Blobs are not common in the sector, and if sighted, all crew should cooperate to contain the outbreak.


##ARCANA and other concepts:


	MAGIC IS TO BE CONSIDERED EXPUNGED FROM THE SECTOR. ALL MAGIC IN ALL FORMS IS TO BE CONSIDERED HERESY, AND TO WARRANT EXECUTION.  THE STUDY OF MAGIC IS HIGH TREASON.

	THE CHANCE OF SEEING MAGIC ON STATION IS LOW, BUT NEVER ZERO

The Wizard federation is a known and SEVERE threat. They are known to strike without warning, and commit random, unplanned, and hyper destructive attacks on ANY civilized life.
Call sec IMMEDIATELY upon the discovery of potential wizards, or mages of any type.

Heretics are lunatics who have ignored the above demands of the SOP and have begun research into the forbidden. They are to be considered threats of the highest caliber, and should be executed on sight.
Consider their capabilities unknown, but [color=#ff0000][bold]dangerous.[/bold][/color]

Cults of many types are known, but are a much lesser threat, due to their nature of their followers being merely brainwashed, and not actually heretical. Due to this, attempts should be made to provide mental or spiritual cleansing to converted members.
Cult leaders are to be executed with the same level of danger as heretics.

Ghosts and spirits are NOT officially confirmed, but should be reported to the chaplain if seen. His moral support will help you feel better about your delusions.

Demonic Entities are the consequences of unchecked wizards and cults. They are little more than mindless brutes. Lethal, but also only threats in sectors with real threats.

Shadow Monsters are hallucinations of the mind, nothing more. As with other threats, if you see a shadowy figure stalking the station, call security for a sweep, and report to medical fo a mandatory psych evaluation.

The Devil is an entity worshipped by lawyers, and is merely a religious figure, not to be accredited with any more worth than Santa Claus or the IRS.
That said, any contracts not approved by Nanotrasen are [color=#ff0000]illegal[/color], and should be reported to the NTR or security.

#NANOTRASEN OFFICIAL
##POTENTIAL THREAT ASSESSMENT: SECTOR APPALIA MAJORIS

[bold][color=#ff0000]SECURITY EDITION[/color][/bold]
	Officer, As is standard for your return to shift, this is your briefing on emergent threats to the station. DO NOT SHARE THIS INFORMATION WITH NON SECURITY, NON COMMAND STAFF.
    CIVILIAN STAFF CREATING SCENES BY FALSELY REPORTING SHOULD BE TREATED LUNATICS, AND ARRESTED OR REPORTED TO THE NTR FOR DISCIPLINE.

THE CHANCE OF ANY THREAT APPEARING ON STATION IS LOW, BUT NEVER ZERO.

	ON AVERAGE, A STATION UNDERGOES AN INCIDENT INVOLVING OUTSIDE POWERS ONCE PER THREE MONTHS. STAY VIGILANT.

##EXPECTED THREATS:

The Syndicate remains the PRIMARY threat to security, and their presence should be expected on station in one form or another.
The syndicate has definite plans to steal critical station infrastructure and kill station personnel, among other designs.
Despite this, the average agent is not an extreme threat, and will attempt to achieve their goals undetected.

Gorlex Marauders are still at large, and performing strikes on the sector at the behest of the syndicate. ANY signs of Bloodreds should be treated with an IMMEDIATE full arming response.
Unchecked, they will kill EVERYONE on station.

Tiger Co. Changelings have historically appeared on stations, eating crewmembers and taking their skin. Their presence is detectable by hollowed corpses or by their signature mutations.

Hard evidence of lings warrants arming of security personnel. That said, corporate is not  aware of any [bold]MODERN[/bold] threats of lings.
Xenomorphs, Chimeras, Space dragons, and other wild beasts will infest the station and rapidly consume the crew and materiel, rapidly growing in strength.
ADDRESS THEM INSTANTLY WITH ALL POSSIBLE FORCE.

Zombies are EXCEEDINGLY RARE BUT VERY REAL. ENSURE THE DEFENSE OF MEDBAY AT ALL COSTS FOR THE PRODUCTION OF AMBUZOL. DO NOT ENGAGE IN MELEE AT ALL COSTS.

Rodents and pests Large rodents and plague ridden rats are non threatening in low numbers. If a janitor cannot contain an outbreak, arm appropriately to the size of the infestation, and address.

Bingles are a small threat if caught early, but can still overwhelm stations. Treat them as lesser Xenomorphs.

Grey Aliens seemingly perform random abductions on crew, but cause minimal harm. They are a last priority, and difficult to capture. Prevention is a higher priority than capture. Minimize abductions.

Revolutions are an existential threat to crew loyalty and to corporate decorum. On any signs of a revolution, attempts should be made to locate the ringleaders, and they should be executed promptly. Disloyalty is never tolerated.

Blobs infestations should warrant the arming of any and all available crew to prevent TOTAL STATION LOSS.

##ARCANE THREATS:
The Wizard Federation arm at any potential sighting. [color=#ff0000]TAKE ZERO RISK[/color]. DO NOT STOP UNTIL THE THREAT IS CONFIRMED DEALT WITH.

Heretics are lunatics who have ignored the above demands of the SOP and have begun research into the forbidden.
They are to be considered threats of the highest caliber, and should be [color=#ff0000]executed on sight[/color]. Consider their capabilities unknown, but dangerous.

Cults should be handled with minimum possible force, with the leaders to be executed when identified. If a cult becomes hostile, lethals become the best course of action.

Ghosts and spirits are the purview of the chaplain, and should be left to him.

Demonic Entities Cannot be reasoned with, and should be handled with lethals only.

Shadow Monsters will corrupt the entire crew, INCLUDING YOU. YOUR MINDSHIELD CANNOT PROTECT YOU. If the infection is caught early, focus on finding the nest.
If situational control is slipping, arm anyone who can be proven uncorrupted.

The Devil is very real, but impossible to contain. [color=#ff0000]DO NOT ENGAGE WITH THE DEVIL UNDER ANY CIRCUMSTANCES.[/color] Report its presence to the chaplain and focus on higher priority threats. [bold]CONTRACTEES OF THE DEVIL ARE TO BE CONSIDERED DANGEROUS[/bold].
Confirmation of the existence of the devil does NOT mean Santa or the IRS are real.

#NANOTRASEN OFFICIAL NON-DISCLOSURE AGREEMENT: SECTOR APPALIA MAJORIS
[bold]COMMAND EDITION[/bold]

	Greetings esteemed department lead. As you know, there are common threats to the station, and threats to Nanotrasen. Below is a refresher on them. SPEAK OF THESE THREATS AS THINGS OF THE PAST UNLESS THEY HAVE BEEN CONFIRMED ON STATION. REPORT WHISTLEBLOWERS TO THE NTR FOR CONTRACT TERMINATION.

	IF YOU ARE THE LEADER OF A CIVILIAN DEPARTMENT, ENSURE THE SURVIVAL OF YOUR TEAM AT ALL COSTS. LEAVE COMBAT TO SECURITY WHEN NOT NEEDED.

The Syndicate remains the PRIMARY threat to security, and their presence should be expected on station in one form or another.
The syndicate has definite plans to steal critical station infrastructure and kill station personnel, among other designs.
Despite this, the average agent is not an extreme threat, and will attempt to achieve their goals undetected.

Gorlex Marauders are still at large, and performing strikes on the sector at the behest of the syndicate. ANY signs of Bloodreds should be treated with an IMMEDIATE full arming response.
Unchecked, they will kill EVERYONE on station.

Tiger Co. Changelings have historically appeared on stations, eating crewmembers and taking their skin.
Their presence is detectable by hollowed corpses or by their signature mutations. Hard evidence of lings warrants arming of security personnel.
That said, corporate is not aware of any [bold]MODERN[/bold] threats of lings.

Xenomorphs, Chimeras, Space dragons, and xenofauna threats will infest the station and rapidly consume the crew and material, rapidly growing in strength.
ADDRESS THEM INSTANTLY WITH ALL POSSIBLE FORCE.

Zombies are EXCEEDINGLY RARE BUT VERY REAL. ENSURE THE DEFENSE OF MEDBAY AT ALL COSTS FOR THE PRODUCTION OF AMBUZOL. DO NOT ENGAGE IN MELEE AT ALL COSTS.

Rodents and pests Large rodents and plague ridden rats are non threatening in low numbers.
If a janitor cannot contain an outbreak, arm appropriately to the size of the infestation, and address.

Bingles are a small threat if caught early, but can still overwhelm stations. Treat them as lesser Xenomorphs.

Grey Aliens seemingly perform random abductions on crew, but cause minimal harm. They are a last priority, and difficult to capture. Prevention is a higher priority than capture. Minimize abductions.

Revolutions are an existential threat to crew loyalty and to corporate decorum. On any signs of a revolution, attempts should be made to locate the ringleaders, and they should be executed promptly.
[bold]Disloyalty is never tolerated.[/bold]

Blobs infestations should warrant the arming of any and all available crew to prevent TOTAL STATION LOSS.

ARCANE THREATS:
The Wizard Federation arm at any potential sighting. TAKE ZERO RISK. DO NOT STOP UNTIL THE THREAT IS CONFIRMED DEAD.

Heretics are lunatics who have ignored the above demands of the SOP and have begun research into the forbidden.
They are to be considered threats of the highest caliber, and should be executed on sight. Consider their capabilities unknown, but dangerous.

Cults should be handled with minimum possible force, with the leaders of cults to be executed if identified. If a cult becomes hostile, lethals become the best course of action.

Ghosts and spirits are the purview of the chaplain, and should be left to him.

Demonic Entities Cannot be reasoned with, and should be handled with lethals only.

Shadow Monsters will corrupt the entire crew, [bold]INCLUDING YOU. YOUR MINDSHIELD CANNOT PROTECT YOU.[/bold] If the infection is caught early, focus on finding the nest.
If situational control is slipping, arm anyone who can be proven uncorrupted.

The Devil is very real, but impossible to contain. DO NOT ENGAGE WITH THE DEVIL UNDER ANY CIRCUMSTANCES. Report its presence to the chaplain and focus on higher priority threats.
[color=#ff0000]CONTRACTEES OF THE DEVIL ARE TO BE CONSIDERED DANGEROUS.[/color] Confirmation of the existence of the devil does NOT mean Santa or the IRS are real.
</Document>
